Havan After Guru Puja With 115 Names Of The Sat Guru 1979-12-02
Lễ Havan sau Lễ Guru Puja với 115 danh hiệu của Sat Guru 1979-12-02
1 Bhavaya
1 Bhavaya
He is the emotions
Ngài là những cảm xúc
2 Sattvatmane
2 Sattvatmane
Whose atma has expressed the truth
Atma của Ngài đã thể hiện sự thật
3 Sattvasagaraya
3 Sattvasagaraya
Who is the ocean of truth
Ngài là đại dương của sự thật
4 Sattvavidhe
4 Sattvavidhe
Who knows the pure vidya
Ngài là người biết vidya thuần khiết
5 Sattvasakshine
5 Sattvasakshine
He is the one who sees the essence
Ngài là người nhìn thấy bản chất
6 Sattvasatyaya
6 Sattvasatyaya
Who meditates on the essences
Ngài là người thiền định về những tinh hoa
7 Amaradhipaya
7 Amaradhipaya
He is the eternal lord
Ngài là vị Chúa vĩnh hằng
8 Bhutakrute
8 Bhutakrute
He is the one who creates the past
Ngài là người tạo ra quá khứ
9 Bhutaprete
9 Bhutaprete
He is the killer of the past
Ngài là người tiêu diệt quá khứ
10 Bhutatmane
10 Bhutatmane
He is the essence of the past
Ngài là tinh hoa của quá khứ
11 Bhutasambhavaya
11 Bhutasambhavaya
Who incarnates as the past
Ngài là người hóa thân thành quá khứ
12 Bhutabhavaya
12 Bhutabhavaya
He is the emotions of all that is so far created
Ngài là cảm xúc của vạn vật đã được tạo ra cho đến nay
13 Bhavaya
13 Bhavaya
He is the emotions
Ngài là những cảm xúc
14 Bhutavide
14 Bhutavide
Who is an expert in all the vidyas that have been so far
Ngài là chuyên gia về tất cả các vidya đã có cho đến nay
15 Bhutakaranaya
15 Bhutakaranaya
He is the cause of all that is created
Ngài là nguyên nhân của vạn vật được tạo ra
16 Bhutasakshine
16 Bhutasakshine
He is the witness of all that is created
Ngài là nhân chứng của vạn vật được tạo ra
17 Prabhutaye
17 Prabhutaye
He is the one who enlightens all that is created
Ngài là người khai sáng cho vạn vật được tạo ra
18 Bhutanangparamagataye
18 Bhutanangparamagataye
The one who takes all that is created beyond
Đấng đưa vạn vật được tạo ra vượt ra ngoài
19 Bhutasangavidhatmane
19 Bhutasangavidhatmane
The one who resides with all that is created
Đấng ngự cùng vạn vật được tạo ra
20 Bhutatmane
20 Bhutatmane
The one who resides in the spirit of all that is created
Đấng ngự trong spirit của vạn vật được tạo ra
21 Bhutashankaraya
21 Bhutashankaraya
The one who is the Shankara of all that is created
Đấng là Shankara của vạn vật được tạo ra
22 Mahanathaya
22 Mahanathaya
He is the great Nath, the Guru, the Lord of the vidya
Ngài là Nath vĩ đại, là Guru, là Chúa của vidya
23 Adi Nathaya
23 Adi Nathaya
He is the primordial master
Ngài là vị thầy nguyên thủy
24 Maheshwaraya
24 Maheshwaraya
He is the greatest God
Ngài là vị Thượng đế vĩ đại nhất
25 Sarva Bhutanirvasatmane
25 Sarva Bhutanirvasatmane
He resides in every spirit of all that is created
Ngài ngự trong mọi spirit của vạn vật được tạo ra
26 Bhutasankarparnashina
26 Bhutasankarparnashina
He destroys all the tension and heat that is created among human beings
Ngài phá hủy mọi căng thẳng và nóng giận được tạo ra giữa con người
27 Sarvatmane
27 Sarvatmane
He resides in all the atman’s
Ngài ngự trong tất cả các atman
28 Sarvaprete
28 Sarvaprete
Who can be achieved by everyone. He is the one who encompasses
Đấng mà mọi người đều có thể đạt được. Ngài là đấng bao trùm tất cả
29 Sarvaya
29 Sarvaya
He is everything
Ngài là tất cả mọi thứ
30 Sarvajnaya
30 Sarvajnaya
He is all the knowledge
Ngài là tất cả tri thức
31 Sarvanirnanaya
31 Sarvanirnanaya
He is the judgement of everyone
Ngài là sự phán xét của mọi người
32 Sarvasakshine
32 Sarvasakshine
He is the witness of everyone
Ngài là nhân chứng của mọi người
(Now, see this is for you to remember
(Bây giờ, hãy xem đây là điều để các con ghi nhớ
that you are going to be a witness of everything
rằng các con sẽ trở thành nhân chứng của mọi thứ
you will see everything you need not say everything
các con sẽ thấy mọi thứ, các con không cần phải nói ra mọi thứ
see, condemning anyone but you know everything)
thấy không, lên án bất kỳ ai nhưng các con biết mọi thứ)
33 Brihahanave
33 Brihahanave
He is the Surya, the sun
Ngài là Surya, là mặt trời
34 Sarvavidhe
34 Sarvavidhe
He is the knower of all knowledge
Ngài là người biết mọi kiến thức
35 Sarvamangalaya
35 Sarvamangalaya
He is all that is auspicious.
Ngài là tất cả những gì tốt lành.
Whatever he does is auspicious
Bất cứ điều gì Ngài làm đều tốt lành
36 Shantaya
36 Shantaya
His the one who is peaceful
Ngài là người bình an
37 Satyaya
37 Satyaya
He is the one who is truth
Ngài là người là chân lý
38 Samaya
38 Samaya
He is with the maya
Ngài ở cùng với maya
39 Purnaya
39 Purnaya
He is complete
Ngài là sự trọn vẹn
40 Ekakine
40 Ekakine
He is lonely. He has no friend
Ngài cô độc. Ngài không có bạn bè
41 Kamalapataye
41 Kamalapataye
He is Vishnu
Ngài là Vishnu
42 Ramaya
42 Ramaya
He is Rama
Ngài là Rama
43 Ramapriyaya
43 Ramapriyaya
Rama is very fond of him
Rama rất yêu quý Ngài
44 Viramaya
44 Viramaya
Everything ends at him. He is the full stop
Mọi thứ kết thúc ở Ngài. Ngài là dấu chấm hết
45 Ramakaranaya
45 Ramakaranaya
He is the cause of Rama
Ngài là nguyên nhân của Rama
46 Shuddhatmane
46 Shuddhatmane
He is of pure heart
Ngài có trái tim thuần khiết
47 Anantaya
47 Anantaya
He is eternal
Ngài là vĩnh hằng
48 Paramatabrute
48 Paramatabrute
Who achieves the ultimate meaning
Người đạt được ý nghĩa tối thượng
49 Hamsasakshine
49 Hamsasakshine
Who is the witness of Hamsa that is Pranava, discrimination.
Người là nhân chứng của Hamsa, đó là Pranava, sự phân định.
50 Vibhave
50 Vibhave
Who is the lord of the whole universe
Người là chúa tể của toàn vũ trụ
51 Prabhave
51 Prabhave
He is the one who is the enlightenment of all that has been created
Ngài là người khai sáng cho tất cả những gì đã được tạo ra
52 Pralaya
52 Pralaya
He is the one who is the destroyer of all that is created
Ngài là người hủy diệt tất cả những gì được tạo ra
53 Siddhatmane
53 Siddhatmane
The one who is a realised soul
Người là một linh hồn khai ngộ
54 Paramatmane
54 Paramatmane
The one who is the highest spirit
Người là spirit tối cao
55 Siddhanan Paramagataye
55 Siddhanan Paramagataye
He is the one who takes us to the highest stages of spirituality
Ngài là người đưa chúng ta đến những giai đoạn cao nhất của tâm linh
56 Siddhi Siddhaye
56 Siddhi Siddhaye
He is the Siddhi and he is the Siddha (power and master of the power)
Ngài là Siddhi và Ngài là Siddha (sức mạnh và chủ nhân của sức mạnh)
57 Sahajaya
57 Sahajaya
He is the Sahaja, spontaneous
Ngài là Sahaja, tự nhiên
58 Vijvaraya
58 Vijvaraya
The one who never gets heated
Người không bao giờ nổi nóng
59 Mahabahave
59 Mahabahave
The one whose arms are very strong
Người có cánh tay rất khỏe
60 Vaholanadavadanaya
60 Vaholanadavadanaya
He is the one who gives the greatest joy
Ngài là người ban tặng niềm vui sướng lớn lao nhất
61 Avayaktapurushaya
61 Avayaktapurushaya
He is the one who is not manifested
Ngài là người không hiển lộ
62 Prajnya
62 Prajnya
He is enlightened awareness
Ngài là nhận thức đã được khai sáng
63 Parijnaya
63 Parijnaya
He is beyond all awareness
Ngài vượt trên mọi nhận thức
64 Paramatadrushe
64 Paramatadrushe
The one who caters for the emancipation of others
Người chăm lo cho sự giải thoát của người khác
65 Panditaya
65 Panditaya
The one who is very much learned.
Người rất uyên bác.
66 Buddhaya
66 Buddhaya
The one who is the knower, the enlightened
Người là người hiểu biết, người đã được khai sáng
67 Vishwatmane
67 Vishwatmane
The one who is the spirit of the whole universe
Ngài là spirit của toàn vũ trụ
68 Pranavaya
68 Pranavaya
The one who is the Om
Ngài là Om
69 Pranavatitaya
69 Pranavatitaya
The one who is beyond Pranava
Ngài là đấng vượt trên Pranava
70 Shankaratmane
70 Shankaratmane
The one who is the spirit of Shankara
Ngài là spirit của Shankara
71 Paramaya
71 Paramaya
The one who is beyond maya
Ngài là đấng vượt trên maya
72 Devanam Paramagataye
72 Devanam Paramagataye
The one who takes the Devas also to the Parama state
Ngài là đấng đưa cả các Deva đến trạng thái Parama
73 Achityaya
73 Achityaya
He is beyond attention
Ngài vượt trên sự chú tâm
74 Chaitanakaraya
74 Chaitanakaraya
The one who is the flow of the awareness
Ngài là dòng chảy của nhận thức
75 Chaitana Chitta Vikramaya
75 Chaitana Chitta Vikramaya
The one who is the conquerer of the hero of the chitta
Ngài là đấng chinh phục người hùng của chitta
76 Parabrahmane
76 Parabrahmane
He is the one beyond Brahma
Ngài là đấng vượt trên Brahma
77 Paramjyotise
77 Paramjyotise
He is the highest light
Ngài là ánh sáng tối cao
78 Paramdhamne
78 Paramdhamne
He is the highest abode
Ngài là nơi ở tối cao
79 Param Tapase
79 Param Tapase
He is the greatest tapasi. The man who does the penance
Ngài là tapasi vĩ đại nhất. Người thực hành khổ hạnh
80 Paramsutraya
80 Paramsutraya
Who is the highest thread of the world
Ngài là sợi chỉ tối cao của thế giới
81 Paramtantraya
81 Paramtantraya
Who is the highest mechanism
Ngài là cơ chế tối cao
82 Kshetrajnaya
82 Kshetrajnaya
He is the knower of the field
Ngài là người biết về lĩnh vực này
83 Lokapalaya
83 Lokapalaya
The one who fosters the people
Ngài là đấng nuôi dưỡng mọi người
84 Gunatmane
84 Gunatmane
The one who is the spirit and essence of all the gunas.
Ngài là spirit và tinh túy của tất cả các guna.
85 Ananta Guna Sampanaya
85 Ananta Guna Sampanaya
The one who has unlimited virtues (You cannot count them)
Ngài là đấng có vô số đức hạnh (Các con không thể đếm được)
86 Yajnya
86 Yajnya
The one who is a Yagna.
Ngài là một Yagna.
(Yagna is a fire that burns off everything and gives auspiciousness)
(Yagna là ngọn lửa thiêu rụi mọi thứ và mang lại sự tốt lành)
87 Hiranyagarbhaya
87 Hiranyagarbhaya
He is the creator
Ngài là đấng sáng tạo
88 Shrigarbhaya
88 Shrigarbhaya
He is the womb of the Mother
Ngài là bào thai của Mẹ
89 Suhrudhe
89 Suhrudhe
He is a very good friend
Ngài là một người bạn rất tốt
90 Paramanandaya
90 Paramanandaya
He is the highest joy
Ngài là niềm vui sướng tối cao
91 Satyanandaya
91 Satyanandaya
He is the highest joy of truth
Ngài là niềm vui sướng tối cao của sự thật
92 Chittanandaya
92 Chittanandaya
He is the highest joy of the attention, the chitta, awareness
Ngài là niềm vui sướng tối cao của sự chú tâm, của chitta, của nhận thức
93 Surya Mangala Madyadhaya
93 Surya Mangala Madyadhaya
He resides in the centre of ego
Ngài ngự ở trung tâm của ego
94 Janakaya
94 Janakaya
The father and the father of Shri Sita
Người cha và là cha của Shri Sita
95 Manta Virya
95 Manta Virya
The essence of mantra
Tinh túy của mantra
96 Manta Bijaya
96 Manta Bijaya
He is the seed of mantra
Ngài là hạt giống của mantra
97 Shastravirya
97 Shastravirya
He is the hero of all the shastras, the scriptures
Ngài là người hùng của tất cả các shastra, các kinh sách
98 Ekaiya
98 Ekaiya
He is the only one (who cannot be surpassed by anyone)
Ngài là người duy nhất (không ai có thể vượt qua)
99 Nishkalaya
99 Nishkalaya
He is without any phases, he is complete and celebrated on a Purnima, full moon day
Ngài không có giai đoạn nào, Ngài hoàn hảo và được tôn vinh vào ngày Purnima, ngày trăng tròn
100 Nirantaya
100 Nirantaya
He is eternal
Ngài là vĩnh hằng
101 Sureshwaraya
101 Sureshwaraya
He is God of all the Gods
Ngài là Thượng đế của tất cả các vị Thần
102 Yantra Krute
102 Yantra Krute
He is the creator of the yantra, which is kundalini
Ngài là đấng tạo ra yantra, chính là kundalini
103 Yantrine
103 Yantrine
He is the engineer of the yantra
Ngài là kỹ sư của yantra
104 Yantravidhe
104 Yantravidhe
He is the knowledge of the yantra, that is kundalini
Ngài là kiến thức về yantra, đó là kundalini
105 Yantra Rudra Parajitaya
105 Yantra Rudra Parajitaya
He is the one who defeats all that comes in the way of yantra
Ngài là đấng đánh bại tất cả những gì cản đường yantra
106 Yantra Mataya
106 Yantra Mataya
He resides in the kundalini
Ngài ngự trong kundalini
107 Yantra Karaya
107 Yantra Karaya
He is the one who sustains the kundalini
Ngài là đấng duy trì kundalini
108 Brahmayonaye
108 Brahmayonaye
He is the essence of the Brahma (yoni is the essence)
Ngài là tinh túy của Brahma (yoni là tinh túy)
109 Vishwayonaye
109 Vishwayonaye
He is the power
Ngài là sức mạnh
(yoni is the Prakruti, the power. Yanta’s power is Guru)
(yoni là Prakruti, là sức mạnh. Sức mạnh của Yanta là Guru)
110 Guruve
110 Guruve
We bow to our Guru
Chúng ta cúi đầu trước Guru của chúng ta
111 Brahmane
111 Brahmane
He is Brahma
Ngài là Brahma
112 Trivikramaya
112 Trivikramaya
He is the conquerer of the three worlds
Ngài là đấng chinh phục ba cõi
113 Sahasra Rambha Yodhabhavaya
113 Sahasra Rambha Yodhabhavaya
He fights for the beginning of the thousand years
Ngài chiến đấu cho sự khởi đầu của một nghìn năm
114 Rudraya
114 Rudraya
The power of Rudra is destructive
Sức mạnh của Rudra có tính hủy diệt
115 Hrudhayasthaya
115 Hrudhayasthaya
He resides in the heart
Ngài ngự trong trái tim